all right so yesterday I went to a
cooperative cafe put on by BC
cooperatives no a whatever he might have
missed out though I went to a group of
people who are all in cooperatives
meeting up and heard the term for the
first time although other people might
cream it is not the first time and even
fact said it to me but the first time it
registered in my brain which was a
platform cooperative and I know like
stock sees one and that like now they
exist but in my education with
cooperatives there was three it was
producer as workers and consumers and I
hate the word consumer but that was what
I was creating like no I guess I'm not
I'm creating a platform cooperative and
but instead of which is amazing there
there happening on all over the place
but having a centralized platform
co-operative gives us a way to compete
on a global level that isn't available
in the individual ones and the people at
the co-operative and I at the meeting
were skeptical of the level of
transparency and democracy that I want
to create and how and in their fields
makes complete sense that there's these
competitors that if they have access to
inside information that that puts us at
a disadvantage and I don't agree with
that at all because we to some degree
aren't competition for Facebook but yet
we are like Facebook can't truly compete
within cooperative a cooperative can
absolutely compete with anything that's
out there especially a global massive
cooperative that isn't all of these
individual ones but like a big where we
get together and create platform
cooperative after platform cooperative
after platform cooperative to help
people live better lives how people
connect people help people get
information to access and understand our
own data so we can create new platform
cooperatives that use that data to make
our lives better what do you eat what do
you what's your grocery shopping and
then how can you work with your
neighbors to reduce your costs reduce
the time you spend and and invite people
to participate or not anything we create
together a lot of it isn't isn't
reinventing the wheel it's looking or
it's out there and what needs to be done
now but eventually it's going to be
recreating all the wheels because the
wheels aren't efficient when they're all
in different directions and working for
the
profit of a select few in their own
organization so having the Netflix of
platform cooperatives we're like you pay
$10 a month and you get a vote in all of
those platform properties because it's
owned by one umbrella co-operative and
that means you get to have access to
ones that help you eat better and help
your finances and help you understand
who to vote for in politics and
understand what to buy that's
enlightenment with your values to help
you find community to connect with and
how we create that together and this is
the big part where they were like
transparence he's not going to work
because the inside is messy and chaotic
oh my god I know I'm all for messy and
chaotic in public I it does mean that
the public I to some degree like we're
gonna piss people off that are in the
group yeah but seeing how the sausage is
made
if you then don't want to eat the
sausage maybe you shouldn't have been
eating the sausage if you don't want to
see that the Board of Directors is is
arguing amongst each other to come to a
decision and making mistakes and then
having to correct them if you don't want
to be on that board that is totally
understandable which is why only people
who want that are gonna be able to be on
the board only people who will do it on
camera and as this community we're not
doing it live on Twitter's of the world
KC we're doing it Archive so that our
members can see and transparent because
someone else brought up the point of
like well there is all the information
out there about our politicians but and
so they are transparent it's just not
available I'm like yeah transparency
also includes understanding the
information not just spewing it all out
there but putting it in a usable format
and so most of my ideas kind of stem
from platform cooperatives that we can
create together where everyone who has
an idea for a platform cooperative has a
way to make it happen because one person
is they're gonna competence all the same
issues that a regular app developer
comes up with is there enough use is
there enough users to make this viable
how do we make money at it how do we
stay afloat so because of the other two
how do we market so we get more of those
people and all of those things every
person has to come up with it so the
same ideas come up with again and again
and again like share food with your
neighbors cook a meal and then there's
never like the threshold of usability so
that it stays there and every people
spend tens of thousands hundreds of
thousand dollars to develop an app but
then is never used by people and even
though it's of
brilliant idea so taking that system of
creating apps but doing it in the open
transparently and democratically or were
not everyone's gonna get everything they
want that's not how the world works most
people will get most of what they want
most of the time especially when it's
progression so the first app that's
being made might not be your your
favorite thing but then it like the next
one in the next one in the next one we
have enough of them and when we unlock
simultaneous projects there's gonna be
something for everyone my issue is that
I actually I want tech people I'd love
people's expertise it's not I don't want
to come off the night I don't but what I
want to create tech for and with are
people who don't necessarily use
technology or use it but don't
necessarily know how to code it I don't
want to create tech for the techies I
want to create for everyone and that's
where the diversity value comes in that
we need to be able to understand that
there's intelligence there's dozens of
intelligence and we all exist along a
spectrum and all of those come we need
to honor that and every single person on
this planet is as valuable as the next
person and the next person truly deeply
my core even when I'm not necessarily
going out on a daily level because I'm
human I still let my core believe no
matter what your talents are no matter
what your emotions are you're just as
valuable as me and everybody else and I
figured out I'm creating a platform
collaborative